Hi everybody.
大家好
My name is Julian Fernandez-Campon,
我是Julian Fernandez-Campon
I am chief technology officer at Tedial.
我是Tedial的首席技术官
And today I'm going to show you a different approach to
今天我要展示一种全新方法
maximize the media production on the web.
可以最大化提升网络媒体生产效率
The use of the no-code iPaaS for media. slide-3
即媒体无代码iPaaS的使用 slide-3
The current workflow paradigm has two main problems. 8-p
目前的工作流程范式主要有两个问题 8-p
The first one is that each system
首先是 平台中集成的
which is integrated in the platform, or two systems that
每一个系统 或需集成的两个系统
need to be integrated, need to know the API of each other.
都需要知道对方的API
This has the problem that it is difficult to evolve.
这有一个问题 就是它很难升级
It is difficult to maintain
很难维护
And if we make a change in one of the APIs of one system,
如果我们改变了一个系统的API
it will be affecting to all the other system which are
这会对集成的其它系统
integrated with it. 16-p
产生影响 16-p
The second one is that we need to be adding
第二个问题是需要在工作流程中
non-specific business steps to the workflows.
增加非具体的业务步骤
For example, moving one media to another location
比如 对媒体文件进行移动操作
or doing transformation to the information
或者对来自一个系统的
which is coming from one system.
信息进行转换
And again, this makes the solution
这同样使得解决方案
and the workflows difficult to evolve and maintain. slide-4
和工作流程难以改进和维护 slide-4
The solution for this is to have a centralized platform
解决办法是建立一个集中型平台
where all the applications are registered and there is a
所有的应用程序都被注册
single endpoint to access all of them. 27-p
并且能够通过单一终端来访问所有应用 27-p
This concept is not new.
这个概念并不新鲜
It's been around for many years in the IT world.
它在IT界已经存在了很多年
And here we can see, for example,
比如
the Gartner 2021 Magic Quadrant in September,
九月份Gartner 2021魔力象限报告中
where we can see key players like Boomi, MuleSoft.
就有Boomi和MuleSoft这样的关键参与者
And that many of you might be aware of.
你们中的许多人可能也意识到了
But this kind of approach has two main limitations. 34-p
这种方法存在两个关键的不足 34-p
The first one is that it is,
第一个不足是
it doesn't have media management capabilities.
它没有媒体管理的能力
It is mainly focused on the control and integrating
它的重心偏向控制和系统整合
systems without any kind of media management.
缺乏媒体管理功能
And the second one is that it is not aware we can say,
第二个不足是它不能识别
it is not aware of multi-site or even multi-cloud. slide-5
多站点甚至多云端 slide-5
If we translate the concept of the iPaaS
如果我们转变iPaaS的理念
to create a no-code iPaaS for media,
创造用于媒体的无代码iPaaS
what we will achieve is that all the workflows that we have
我们就能做到将这些
that have like, in this one, many
特定活动或特定操作的
specific activities or many specific operations,
全部工作流程
which are not part of the business,
完全删除掉
we will get rid of all of them.
因为它们都不是业务的组成部分
And we will have any workflow, which is really simple.
我们会设置十分简洁的工作流程
It is oriented to the business. 50-p
这些流程完全是业务导向 50-p
Like in this case, for example,
比如这个案例中
we have a simple workflow where we have the ingest edit,
我们有一个简单的工作流程 有摄入编辑
Auto QC, validate and the final delivery. 53-p
自动质量控制 验证和最终交付 53-p
It has several advantages. So first of all,
它有几个优点
is that it is simple, it is easy to read.
首先 它很简单 很容易读懂
The second one is that it is focused on the business.
第二 它专注于业务
So we don't need experts or IT people to be reading
我们不需要专家或IT人员来
the workflow and evolving the workflow.
阅读和升级工作流程
And also it's easy to design. slide-6
还有 它很容易设计 slide-6
All of this is really good, but to achieve this,
这些都非常棒 但是要达到这一点
the no-code iPaaS for media,
媒体无代码iPaaS
we need to standardize different things. 62-p
我们需要将不同的东西标准化 62-p
The first one is the data model that we can go for the
第一个是数据模型 可以用于编辑
editorial for the EBU Core and for everything which is
用于EBU核心 用于摄像机
related for the cameras to the SMPTE ST 2065. 65-p
甚至SMPTE ST 2065 65-p
Secondly, we need to standardize the APIs so that
其次 我们需要对API进行标准化
all the systems which are in the platform are speaking
这样平台上所有系统都说同样的语言
the same language and they are presenting the same methods. 68-p
提供相同的工作方法 68-p
And finally, we need to standardize in some way that
最后 我们需要以某种方式
web browsers, so that we can have
对网络浏览器进行标准化
media management capabilities or media management features
这样我们就有了媒体管理功能
where the media, the audio subtitles
这样不管是媒体 音频字幕
and the broadcast media can be played
还有广播媒体都可以
and can be presented in a single way. slide-7
用统一的方式进行呈现 slide-7
What is the value proposition of
媒体无代码iPaaS的
the no-code iPaaS for media? 77-p
价值主张是什么 77-p
First of all, is that
首先是
the applications are integrated with the platform.
应用程序与平台的整合
So we can say that we have a one to many similar
这样我们就有一对多的类似整合
integrations and the meaning of this is
这意味着
that every system
每一个功能相同的系统
which is doing the same thing will be sent the same method. 83-p
都会被发送同样的方法 83-p
For example, if we have a transcoder,
例如 如果有一个转码器
the method will be "transcode", and if we have one AI tool,
方法将是“转码” 如果是AI工具
it will be "analyze" and so on.
方法就是“分析” 诸如此类
In this case, we won't have a vendor lock-in
这样我们就不会有供应商锁定
because if we want to exchange
因为如果我们想要将解码器
one transcoder for another or one AI tool for another,
或AI工具换成另一个
it will be really simple and easy to do. 90-p
将会非常简单 90-p
Legacy MAMs can also be integrated as another system
传统的MAMs也可以被整合成另一个系统
because the key concept here is
因为关键的一点是
that the solution is not demand that
这里的解决方案
has orchestration capabilities.
并不对协调能力做要求
The solution is one integration platform that can be
该解决方案是一个集成平台
integrated one MAM,
可以集成一个MAM
but also can be integrated another legacy MAM,
也可以集成
which is in operation and the customers,
另一个在工作中的传统MAM
they don't want to change at this point. 99-p
特别是在客户并不希望更换的情况下 99-p
And finally, it will be easy to implement all the workflows because it
最后 很容易实现所有的工作流程
will be using a no-code approach so that all the people,
因为它将使用无代码的方法
without deep technical knowledge can be creating the
这样没有深厚技术知识的人也可以
workflows, understanding the workflows
创建工作流程 理解工作流程
and dragging and dropping the different boxes,
并拖放不同的工作模块
which are part of it. slide-8
这也是平台的一部分 slide-8
What are the three pillars of the no-code iPaaS for media? 107-p
媒体无代码iPaaS的三大支柱是什么 107-p
The first one is a common workspace where all the
第一个是公共工作空间
applications will be accessing to get the media.
所有应用程序都访问这个空间获取文件
And this is aligned with the 2030
这个和2030 MovieLabs Vision的操作一致
MovieLabs Vision that the media has to stay in the
即媒体文件必须
original location,
留在原来的位置
not to be moved between different applications,
而不是在不同的应用之间移动
because that will be really inefficient. 114-p
因为那将是非常低效的 114-p
The second one is to have a common workspace.
第二个是要有一个共同的工作空间
This is what we have discussed before,
这就是我们刚讨论过的
that all the applications that are doing the same function
所有功能相同的应用
need to be presenting the same method.
都需要提供相同的方法
This is what they said before,
这就是之前所说的
about the one to many integrations. 120-p
关于一对多的整合 120-p
And finally, all the obligations needs to be speaking the same language.
最后 所有的规范都需要同一种语言
It means that the data model,
这就意味着
which is used for each of the application needs to be
每一个应用使用的数据模型都需要
translated into the no-code iPaaS for media data model and
转译为媒体无代码iPaaS数据模型
each plugging or each application is responsible for
每一个插件或者应用都能够读取
reading the iPaaS data model
iPaaS数据模型
and writing into the iPaaS data model.
都能够写入iPaaS数据模型
So that if there is another task,
这样 如果有另一个任务
which depends on the output of a previous task,
依赖于前一个任务的输出
it doesn't have to understand the specific data model of
它就不需要理解前一个系统
the previous system. 130-p
特有的数据模型了 130-p
A typical example is
一个典型的例子是
one AI system, which is providing some annotations
有一个AI系统为媒体文件提供注释
about the media, and the next system
然后有另一个系统
which is using data annotation to take some decision,
要使用这些数据注释
to be validating the content or to do any automatic action.
对文件内容进行验证或者进行自动化操作
It doesn't need to know what is the specific data model of
这个系统就不需要去理解
the previous AI system. slide-9
之前AI系统独有的数据模型 slide-9
Here in this diagram,
在这个图中
we can see three components of the no-code iPaaS for media,
可以看到媒体无代码iPaaS的三个组件
the first one, and really key,
第一个是最关键的部分
and this is a real enabler of the no-code iPaaS for
也是媒体无代码iPaaS的功能核心
media is the media extraction layer.
就是媒体提取层
It will provide the multi-site capabilities
它将提供多站点能力
and the access to the multiple technologies of the storage.
还有对多种存储技术的支持
In our case,
具体来讲
we have a aSTORM which is a storage management system.
我们有aSTORM存储管理系统
Then we need to have a MAM, which is optional
然后 我们需要MAM 我之前说过
as I mentioned before, in this case, we have Evo,
这是可选的 在这里 我们还有Evo
which also comes from Tedial. 150-p
同样由Tedial出品 150-p
And finally, we need to have one intelligent BPM,
最后 我们需要智能BPM
which is going one level up to the traditional BPMs to allow
这个比传统BPM更高级的BPM
these local no-code paradigm and be able to define and
可以让本地无代码范式更加容易地
implement the workflows really easily. And in the bottom,
定义和实施工作流程
we need to have all the business intelligence, maintenance,
在底层 我们需要有所有的业务智能 维护
user management and everything
用户管理和其他
which is needed to be modifying and to be monitoring the
对平台进行调整和
platform. slide-10
监测 slide-10
Here, we can see all the other elements,
这里 我们可以看到所有其他元素
which are integrated within the platform,
它们被整合在平台内
which are managed in the same way
与其它组件一起
as the other components. slide-11
以同样的方式被管理 slide-11
And here, if we focus on the data model standardization,
如果我们专注于数据模型的标准化
we can see that the EBU Core is a good option to be
可以看到EBU核心是
standardized in the data model, as it has several objects,
数据模型标准化的一个很好的选择
which are, for example,
因为它有几个对象 比如说
the editorial metadata, publishing entities,
编辑元数据 出版实体
planning, distribution,
计划 分配
which is really useful for this kind of workflows,
这对需要保存信息的
where do we need to be keeping the information. 172-p
此类工作流程十分有益 172-p
The good thing,
好的方面 或者说
or a good practice is that if we go to a microservices
好的做法是 如果我们采用微服务的方法
approach, each microservice is updating a piece
每个微服务都在升级
of the data model, which is oriented to the business. slide-12
一块业务导向的数据模块 slide-12
If we think about the data model standardization
如果我们考虑到所有摄像
which is needed for all the cameras, acquisition,
采集 制作所需数据模型的标准化
production, ACES is a good candidate
ACES是比EBU核心
better than the EBU Core.
更好的选择
Why? Because many vendors are now supporting ACES.
因为许多供应商现在都支持ACES
There are workflows which are working,
一些基于ACES的现成工作流程
and which are very well-defined based on ACES.
十分明确并且正在有效运转
And also the data model is really well organized in
而且 在摄像机 镜头 记录器和其他方面
camera objects, lenses, recorders and many other things. 185-p
这个数据模型也组织得很好 185-p
So keeping this information in the SMPTE ST 2065
所以在SMPTE ST 2065中记录信息
is also a good option for the no-code iPaaS for media. slide-13
对媒体无代码iPaaS来说也是不错的选择 slide-13
If we go now to the API standardization,
如果现在来看API的标准化
this is what we mentioned before,
这是我们之前提到的
about the one to many. Here,
一对多
we will see what are the benefits that each system will be
我们将看到 如果每个功能相同的系统
presenting the same methods if they do the same thing.
都提供相同的方法 这有什么好处
And also these systems can be organized in different groups. 194-p
还有这些系统可以被分为不同的组 194-p
For example, here, we can see that we have storage engines,
例如 这里我们可以看到存储引擎
media processing engines on other storage engines in the
和在分发另一端的其他存储引擎上的
other end for the distribution. 197-p
媒体处理引擎 197-p
This is also really good in order to implement in the
这对工作流程的实施十分有益
workflows, to have everything organized
一切都组织有序
and be able to swap one component for
可以随时更换组件
another, that we will see later. slide-14
这点我们以后会看到 slide-14
Here, if we think about the different use cases that we have,
如果考虑我们不同的应用实例
the first one can be the simple delivery in the cloud,
第一个可能就是简易云端交付
where we get the content from one S3 bucket,
我们从一个S3存储桶中获取内容
we analyze the content, we transcode it
分析内容并进行转码
and finally we deliver it to another S3 bucket.
最终把它交付到另一个S3存储桶中
And as you see here, this is a very simple linear workflow,
如你所见 这是一个简单的线性工作流程
and we are not adding any non-business specific logic. slide-15
我们没有添加任何非业务的特殊逻辑 slide-15
Another use case is the localization where we receive a
另一个实例是本地化
content in the cloud, one audio track, subtitle,
我们在云中收到音轨 字幕
or both, it is ingested.
或两者皆有 它被抓取
It is seen using a web browser,
并通过网络浏览器呈现
which is supporting the playing of the video and audio,
它支持视频和音频的播放
and also with the synchronization of the audio tracks,
也支持音轨 字幕等的同步
subtitles and everything. And finally, if it is okay,
最终 如果没有问题
if it is correct, it will be delivered to another,
如果准确无误 它就会向另一个目的地
another destination. slide-16
进行交付 slide-16
And here we can see one of the key features of the no-code
这里 我们可以看到媒体无代码iPaaS的
iPaaS for media, which is swappable components.
一个关键特征 就是可替换组件
Remember the workflow that we had for the media distribution
记得媒体云端分发的工作流程吗
in the cloud, where we have the content, we analyze it,
我们获取内容 分析内容
we transcode it and we deliver it to another destination. 225-p
转码并交付到另一个目的地 225-p
If for some reason,
如果出于某些原因
we need to duplicate the workflow because we are receiving
我们需要重复工作流程 因为我们在接收
UHD content and the transcoder we are using is not efficient,
UHD内容 我们的转码器效率不高
or we want to improve the quality of the transcoder,
或者我们需要提升转码的质量
or we want to change that transcoder for another one,
或者我们想要更换
which is more cost effective,
效率更高的转码器
the change is as simple as replacing one box for another,
这个改变就像换箱子一样简单
because, remember, all the applications
因为平台上的
which are in the platform,
所有应用
following the philosophy of the one to many,
都遵从一到多的设计理念
they share the same method. 236-p
它们提供相同的方法 236-p
So the workflow will be unchanged because the only thing
所以工作流程完全不需要改变
that we will be doing is to be using the transcoding method
我们唯一需要做的就是
of the new application in this case, AWS Elemental. slide-17
使用新应用AWS Elemental的转码方法 slide-17
That's all for now.
这就是全部了
Thank you for watching. I hope you have enjoyed it, bye.
多谢观看 希望你们能喜欢